<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Non-Tech on Potato</title><link>https://sneaky-potato.github.io/tags/non-tech/</link><description>Recent content in Non-Tech on Potato</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sneaky-potato.github.io/tags/non-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Writing</title><link>https://sneaky-potato.github.io/blog/literature/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sneaky-potato.github.io/blog/literature/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead !mb-9 text-xl"&gt;
You got me with &amp;rsquo;em thicc words (◡‿◡*).
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to try out writing. Classic English writing, that is, other than the assembly-directive-shenanigans that I&amp;rsquo;m writing nowadays for my assignments (T_T).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="blog"&gt;Blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lol, talking about my blog in another one of my blogs, recursive literature or wot (Related note- &lt;a href="https://stackingthebricks.com/how-blogs-broke-the-web/"&gt;How Blogs Broke The Web&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this blog with nothing particular in my mind. Main objective was to setup the website and maybe show people about what I like / do behind the screen.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gamification</title><link>https://sneaky-potato.github.io/til/gamification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sneaky-potato.github.io/til/gamification/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead !mb-9 text-xl"&gt;
That point when game physics make perfect sense.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are only a few games whose physics and mechanics actually make sense. Unironically people use it in non game envronments with the objective of increasing productivity and interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly successful gamification has sorta become a standard for comparing things. &lt;a href="https://www.duolingo.com/"&gt;Duolingo&lt;/a&gt; in education, &lt;a href="https://www.starbucks.com/rewards"&gt;Starbucks Rewards&lt;/a&gt; in marketing and &lt;a href="https://support.snapchat.com/en-GB/a/snapstreaks"&gt;Snapstreak in Snapchat&lt;/a&gt; are some good examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what about when gamification is applied to life and basic scheduling in routine, &lt;em&gt;hmm&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Survivorship Bias</title><link>https://sneaky-potato.github.io/til/survivorship-bias/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sneaky-potato.github.io/til/survivorship-bias/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead !mb-9 text-xl"&gt;
Another super fancy term for something I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize I knew until I read about it.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wikipedia (saving you from that extra tab in your overly crowded chrome :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survivorship bias, survival bias or immortal time bias is the logical error of concentrating on the people or things that made it past some selection process and overlooking those that did not, typically because of their lack of visibility. This can lead to incorrect conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Structured Procrastination</title><link>https://sneaky-potato.github.io/til/structured-procrastination/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sneaky-potato.github.io/til/structured-procrastination/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead !mb-9 text-xl"&gt;
Getting things done while procrastinating.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is literally a whole website dedicated to this thing &lt;a href="http://www.structuredprocrastination.com/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
The footer of the website captures the main idea -&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Site designed by the author&amp;rsquo;s granddaughter, who did the work while avoiding the far more weighty assignment of her literature test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept has major intersection with the &lt;a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/live-asynchronously-c8e7172fe7ea/"&gt;living asynchronously&lt;/a&gt; idea (do give it a read as well).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing revolves around getting the low priority things done while you&amp;rsquo;re procrastinating the high priority ones. You might not have realized it but at some point you were procrastinating structurally too. I, too found this website while procrastinating some very important stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Devil's Dictionary</title><link>https://sneaky-potato.github.io/til/devils-dictionary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sneaky-potato.github.io/til/devils-dictionary/</guid><description>&lt;div class="lead !mb-9 text-xl"&gt;
Finally some innovation on a dictionary.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no bibliophile but do appreaciate good writing.&lt;br&gt;
That is, while looking for another book to add it to my overflowing stack of &lt;code&gt;not-gonna-read-but-hey-its-cool-ill-read-afterwards&lt;/code&gt; list, (a long pause here) I happened to stumble upon this piece of literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A satirical dictionary written by American journalist Ambrose Bierce, consisting of common words followed by humorous and satirical definitions, I&amp;rsquo;d say it is indeed a fine work of art.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>